So today I want to use my Cerise and my
ART7 Wi-Fi in Blackout.
Let's learn about it.
So in this video, we're going to talk
about using my Cerise
connected to my iPad
through the USB C cable to transmit CRM X
to all my lights, while also having the
ART7 connected to my iPad with Wi-Fi
to check on my Asteras.
These two devices are my favorite combo
right now in Blackout.
But you can do this with any transmitter
that you can hardline
via USB C into your iPad.
So the Rat Pack AKS, the Rat Pack
satellite, really any transmitter with an
ethernet port will work like this, too.
Before we get started, I just want to say
in this video, we're only using the ART7
Wi-Fi box for the Astera
integration in Blackout.
We are not using it as a
node in addition to our Cerise.
You can use your ART7 as an
additional universe, but that requires
networking it together
with your other transmitter.
And I won't be
showing that in this video.
So without further
ado, let's get started.
Okay. The first thing I'm going to do is
open Safari and go to
the IP address of my
series. Now you're welcome to keep the
default IP address that
the Cerise ships with.
I found that I get better results using
this IP address scheme.
If you're not comfortable with
networking, you can just
leave them alone or you can
copy mine. Just note that if you change
the IP address of the
Cerise, that's going
to be the new number that you type into
the web browser to get to the Cerise
configuration page.
I did want to show off this page because
it is really
important that you change set
as default gateway to no. You can do
this by clicking the pencil.
And this is how you change all of your
settings and making sure this is off and
then clicking the checkbox.
Then the web page will prompt you to
reset and you can reset
the device from there.
The page will also tell you that if you
change the IP
address, you'll have to type
in that IP address to
get back to the page.
With that done, let's set up our ART7
Wi-Fi box, a
short press and hold of the
power button turns it on.
Now let's navigate to the
Astera Next app in the Astera page.
I'll go manage Bluetooth bridges.
I'll hit the plus sign and I'll click
this top option for the ART7.
You'll see it pop up here
and I'll hit tap to bond.
You'll notice here it
says connected via Bluetooth.
When using the Astera app, I always
recommend connecting via Bluetooth.
That way you can save the
Wi-Fi features for Blackout.
The other thing I want to
note here is my firmware version.
You have to be on five point fifteen
point one three seven to use the Blackout
integration. If you're not on this
firmware, check out my
Facebook post where I
explain how to update.
You'll come to this side menu.
You'll scroll down to app settings, go to
lights background update and press and
hold this refresh icon and
type in the code Blackout.
I've already done this so I can't show
you much more than this.
But once you hit OK, you'll be prompted
to update with a custom firmware.
And that is five point
fifteen point one three seven.
After you've updated the firmware, reboot
the box and you can keep going with us.
So now that we're on the right firmware,
I'm going to hit this
arrow to go into the
boxes settings or go to Wi-Fi settings
and I'll turn access point on and join
network off and then I'll click done.
At this point, I recommend rebooting the
ART7. Press and hold the power button
and it'll turn off.
Yep. And then short press and hold.
It'll turn back on.
Now we're all done with the Astera app.
Here I am in Blackout and you can see in
link status I'm connected via Ethernet.
I'll click link status
and go to connect to Astera.
I'll add a new Astera box and make sure
I'm on connect via Wi-Fi access point.
Again, this is the
beauty of this whole setup.
I'm connected to my CRM X
transmitter via Ethernet.
This USB cable.
But I can also connect to
my ART7 via its Wi-Fi.
So here we'll put in the pairing pin,
which you can see on a
sticker on the back of
your box. Blackout will then prompt you
to join the network.
I'll click join and it will
ask you to pick a radio pin.
I'll use four eights and
I'll select US Australia.
Then I'll hit connect and you can see
instantly my ART7 pops up.
So let's test this out.
I'll go into patch add
fixtures, go to the cloud database.
I'll search for a Helios tube series.
Let's grab a bunch of pixels, do like
eight pixels and I'll do something crazy.
Like mode 140.
We'll patch that in.
I'll use my white remote
to blue mode my Helios.
There it goes.
Oh my gosh.
At least it's on key side.
Now that it's in blue mode, I'll go to
link status, connect
to a star and I'll hit
pair with lights and
just like that, it connects.
Now in the patch, I'll hit the Astara
logo and I'll hit send
to send it the data for
the patch.
I'll hit enter on the
light and now it's patched.
I'll give it a little test to one at 20.
Looks like it works to me.
And then as you can see up at the top, I
have the battery life.
If I click the Astera logo, I can see the
exact battery life
and I can change any of
the settings I want.
I can flash it white.
I can flash it cyan and I can take back
over with DMX control.
So as you can see, the ART7 and the
Cerise play great together.
The only other tip I have for you is the
Cerise is really strong and it broadcasts
CRMX on 2.4 gigahertz, which is what the
ART7 uses for its wifi.
So I recommend having them
spaced apart a little right now.
They're about a foot away from each other
and it's working great.
So do your own testing, but that's my
only other little recommendation.
So that's how to set this all up.
Let me know in the comments what you want
to see more of, and I'll see you next time.